typecast.com 2018-05-25

# Privacy Policy - Typecast

**As of January 1, 2018, we are no longer providing support for Typecast. Our apologies for the inconvenience. Thank you.**

Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc., a Delaware corporation with its principal place of business at 500 Unicorn Park Drive, Woburn, MA 01801 United States of America, and its subsidiaries and affiliates worldwide (collectively, the “Company” or “Monotype Imaging”) makes information, products, and services available on our Websites (each individually, the “Site” and collectively, the “Sites”), subject to the following Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”). We own and operate many Sites. You can determine if Monotype Imaging is the owner and operator of a site by referring to the Terms and Conditions of Use for the specific site. The Privacy Policy applies to all of our Sites. The owner and operator of the domain [http://typecast.com](http://typecast.com/) is Monotype Ltd, a subsidiary of Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc.

**Monotype Imaging’s Commitment to Personal Information Protection.**   
At Monotype Imaging, we respect your right to privacy. Protecting the security and privacy of your personal information is important to us. We understand that as a visitor to our Site, you prefer to control your own personal information preferences and we give you the option to do so. We hope the policy outlined below will help you understand what personal information we may collect, how we use and safeguard that personal information and with whom we may share it.

**Voluntary Personal Information We May Collect.**   
We may ask you to register or provide personal information and preferences when you visit certain areas of our Site, request information, purchase products or subscribe to company newsletters. When you provide Monotype Imaging with your name, email address, mailing address, or telephone number, and you don’t “opt-out”, we may use this information to alert you to company news, new services and other company and product information. If you don’t want Monotype Imaging or Monotype Imaging representatives to contact you, you may “opt-out” of this preference at any time, whether you’re online or contacting Monotype Imaging directly. You’ll always have the flexibility to “opt-in” at any time based on previous information or newly updated information. See the “How to update your personal information” section for further information.

**Non-Voluntary Personal Information We May Collect.**   
When you browse our Site, you can generally do so anonymously as we don’t collect personal information when you browse; however, your browser automatically tells us the type of computer and operating system you’re using. Like most standard Web site servers, our Site uses log files (cookies). A “cookie” is a small line of text that is stored with your Web browser for record-keeping purposes and helps Monotype Imaging provide better service to you. Your browser has an option to accept, reject or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. Once you enter our Site, a cookie follows as you navigate the site, collecting information including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ overall movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use only, to help us understand what users are seeking on our Site.

**Purpose of Collecting Personal Information.**   
When you do provide us with personal data, we usually use it to respond to your inquiry, process your order or provide you access to specific information or offers. Also, to support our customer relationship with you, we may store and process voluntary and non-voluntary personal data and share it with our worldwide affiliates to better understand your business needs and how we can improve our products and services. If you choose not to have your personal data used to support our customer relationship (especially direct marketing or market research), we will respect your choice. We do not sell or otherwise market your personal data to third parties.

**Limitation on the Purpose.**   
We collect, use or disclose personal information supplied by you only for the purpose(s) initially identified by you, however, in some cases we may use the personal information supplied by you: (i) for any additional purpose that is directly related to the original purpose for which the personal information was collected, including sharing such personal information with a third party vendor if you purchased a product supplied by that third party vendor from one of our Sites, (ii) when it is necessary to prepare, negotiate and perform a contract with you, (iii) when it is required by law or the competent governmental or judicial authorities, (iv) when it is necessary to establish or preserve a legal claim or defense, or (v) when it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activities.

**How We Protect Your Personal Information.**   
Monotype Imaging uses its best efforts to try to protect the personal information that you share with us. Monotype Imaging stores information in a controlled, secure environment. We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, however we only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

**How to Update Your Personal Information or “Opt-out”.** You can help Monotype Imaging maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your name, address, title, phone number, e-mail address or your content preferences. If at any time you wish to update your information or preferences, or you prefer to stop receiving communication from Monotype Imaging, feel free to contact us at any time.

**Links to Other Sites.**   
Our Site may contain links to other Sites. Monotype Imaging assumes no responsibility for the content or the privacy policies and practices of such Web sites. Monotype Imaging encourages you to read the privacy statements of the linked sites as their privacy practices may differ from ours.

**Business Transitions Including Merger or Acquisition.**   
If Monotype Imaging undergoes a business transition such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information may become part of the assets transferred.

**Monotype Imaging Privacy Concerns Contacts.**   
If you want to change your personal information or wish to “opt-out”, please feel free to contact us in the following ways:

**E-mail:**  

**Common Carrier:**  
Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc.  
Attn: Webmaster  
500 Unicorn Park Drive  
Woburn, MA 01801  
USA

Notification of Changes. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement on our Site under the Privacy Policy section. You can determine when these Terms were last revised by referring to the “LAST UPDATED” line at the bottom of these Terms. Your continued use of the Site after any changes to the site will indicate your acceptance of the changes and Terms.

_LAST UPDATED: FEBRUARY 6, 2013_
